Guide to the Kuntu Repertory Theatre Records, 1973-2013 CTC.2015.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Production Records, c. 1947-2013; I.
  - Scripts and Promptbooks, c. 1947-2011; 5.
    - Performed
      - Gospel Choirs: Pslams of Survival in an Alien Land Called Home by Derrick Bell, c. 1996
      - Great Women of Song arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1996, 2001
      - Happy Ending by Douglas Turner Ward, Undated
      - Happy Ending and Day of Absence by Douglas Turner Ward, 1994-1996
      - Harriet Tubman Love Somebody by William F. Mayfield, 1993-2010, Undated
      - Healthy Black Family or The Separation of Blood by Bridgette A. Wimberly, Undated
      - Hieroglyphic Graffiti by Aharon AKA Chadwick A. Boseman, 2000
      - Hold Fast to Dreams by Rob Penny, 1981
      - A Hole in the Dark by Hilly Hicks, 2000
      - The Homecoming by August Wilson, 1976, Undated
      - The Homecoming by August Wilson, Wine in the Wilderness by Alice Childress, and A Question Mark on Your Face by Rob Penny, 1976
      - The House that Carol Built by Frank F. Hightower, 2010-2011, Undated
      - I Am a Black Woman arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1979-1983, Undated
      - I Am a Black Woman and Blues in Jazz Waters arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, Undated
      - In the Midnight Hour by Kathleen Collins, 1980-2006
      - In New England Winter by Ed Bullins, Undated
      - In Splendid Error by William Branch, c. 1986, Undated
      - Indigo Blues by Judi Ann Mason, Undated
      - It's Not About You or Me, It's About Us by Jade Washington, c. 2003
      - Jelly's Last Jam by Gregory C. Wolfe, c. 2005
      - John Edgar Wideman Collage, author not listed, 1990
      - Journey of the Spirits: History of Gospel Music by Ernest McCarty, Undated
      - Just Rob Penny: Black Tones of Truth arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, Undated
      - Keepers of the Dream: A Celebration of Significant Sistahs by Jaqueline Moscou, 1997-1999, Undated
      - Killin' and Chillin' (In the 'Hood) by Rob Penny and Lee Kiburi, 1995-1997, Undated
      - Killing Me Softly by Gloria Browne, 1995-2002
      - Killing Me Softly and Strange Stories from Your Neighborhood by Gloria Browne, 1991, 1995
      - Lavender Lizards and Lilac Landmines: Layla's Dream by ntozake shange, 2002
      - A Liberating Prayer: A Love Song for Mumia by Sybil J. Roberts, 2001-2003
      - Lift Every Voice and Sing, arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1990
      - Lift Every Voice and Sing (In Celebration of Martin Luther King Jr.) arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 2001, Undated
      - Lifting by Frank F. Hightower, 1989-1998
      - Little Willie Armstrong Jones by Rob Penny, 1975-2005, Undated
      - Long Time Since Yesterday by P.J. Gibson, c. 1988
      - Love to All, Lorraine by Elizabeth Van Dyke, 1985
      - A Love Song for Miss Lydia by Don Evans, c. 1989
      - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom by August Wilson, 1987-1988
      - Mahalia Jackson: Standing on Holy Ground by Vernell A. Lillie, 2000-2010, Undated
      - Mediation at Work: A Walk on the Wild Side by Vernell A. Lillie, 1992
      - The Meeting by Jeff Stetson, 1983-1990, Undated
      - The Meeting, Sugar, Africana Reflections: The Past is Prologue, c. 2001
      - Men without Women by Gladys Thomas, Undated
      - The Miracle Church by Sybil Berry, 1992, Undated
      - Miss Dessa by Shirley M. Hardy-Leonard, 1986, 1992
      - Murderer on the Hill District by Rob Penny, 2001
      - A Musical Level of Pain by Joy Jones, 1999
      - Nefertari Rising by Rob Penny, 1999-2000, Undated
      - New Hope, author not listed, Undated
      - A New Vision, A Better Tomorrow arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1977-1978, Undated
      - A Noose for Betty Anne by Javon Johnson, 1998
      - Over Forty by Celeste Walker, c. 1989-c. 1996
      - Pain in My Heart by Rob Penny, Undated
      - Pain in My Heart and Reachings by Rob Penny, 1986, 2008, Undated
      - Papa's Blues by Javon Johnson, 1996-c. 2000, Undated
      - The Past is Prologue arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, Undated
      - Public Images Private Lives by Sybil Berry, Undated
      - A Question Mark on Your Face by Rob Penny, Undated
      - Radio Golf by August Wilson, Undated
      - Raisin by Robert Nemiroff and Charlotte Zaltzberg, 1975, c. 2010
      - Raisin in the Sun by Lorraine Hansberry, 1958, c. 1984
      - Reachings by Rob Penny, 1986, Undated
      - Reachings and Pain in My Heart by Rob Penny, 1986
      - Reflections: Rob Penny's Forum in Flight, 1975, c. 1990, Undated
      - Reflections Standing Tall: Three Forces from African American History, Douglas, Du Bois, Washington, 1994-1995, Undated
      - Relativity by Cassandra Medley, 2006
      - Resurrection of Lady Lester: A Poetic Mood Song Based on the Legend of Lester Young by OyamO, c. 1980
      - The River Niger by Joseoph A. Walker, 1973, c. 1976
      - Roads of the Mountaintop by Ron Milner, 1994-1995, Undated
      - Royal Relations by Valerie Lawrence, 1984-c. 1985
      - Sacred Ground by Ifetayo Valerie Williams Lawrence, 1998, Undated
      - Sarafina! by Mbongeni Ngema, 2007
      - A Season of Love, author not listed, Undated
      - Seven Guitars by August Wilson, 1996
      - Shakin' the Mess Outta Misery by Shay Youngblood, 1988
      - She'll Find Her Way Home by Valetta Anderson, 1991, 2003
      - Sherlock Holmes and the Hands of Othello by Alexander Simmons, c. 1987, Undated
      - Sing Black Hammer by William F. Mayfield, 1993-2005
      - Sister Son/ji by Sonia Sanchez, 1969
      - Slam the Door Softly by Clare Boothe Luce, Undated
      - The Slave by Leroi Jones, Undated
      - Slow Lives on a Humdrum by Rob Penny, c. 1976, Undated
      - Sophisticated Ladies by Donald McKayle and Duke Ellington, c. 1986
      - South African Fireflies arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1990-1992
      - A Star Ain't Nothin' But a Hole in Heaven by Judi Ann Mason, 1977
      - Steal Away by Ramona King, c. 1981
      - Steppin' Into a Winter Wonderland arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, Undated
      - Still I Rise arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1987-1998, Undated
      - Stories About the Old Days by Bill Harris, c. 1990
      - Sun Rising on the Hill District by Rob Penny, 2001-2002, Undated
      - Sweet Thunder by Ben Tyler, 2005
      - Take on a Life or Live in a Crowded/Colored Cocoon by Rob Penny, 1980, c. 1981
      - Tambourines to Glory by Langston Hughes, c. 1959, 1997, Undated
      - Tap Dance Kid by Charles Blackwell, 2000
      - Thinking Outside the Box, author not listed, Undated
      - To Be Young, Gifted, and Black: A Portrait of Lorraine Hansberry in Her Own Words adapted by Robert Nemiroff, 1986
      - To Whom it May Concern by Linda Hunt, 1998, 2003, Undated
      - Toujour Bleu: A Dance Play by Melony McGant and Larry Floyd, 2005
      - Traces (or Boys) by Gregory Kahlil Kareem Allen, 1996-2010, Undated
      - The Trial of One Short-Sighted Black Woman Versus Mammy Louise and Safreeta Mae by Marcia L. Leslie, 1996
      - Trouble in Mind by Alice Childress, 1971, 2010
      - Union Station by Marta Effinger, 1990, 1992, Undated
      - The Vo-Du Macbeth by Lenwood O. Sloan, 2003, Undated
      - W.E.B. DuBois and Booker T. arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, Undated
      - We Come Back Fighting arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1981
      - What Happens to a Dream Deferred arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1965, 1979
      - What'd Ya Do Today, Billy Joe by Eleanor Harder, Undated
      - When the Chickens Came Come to Roost by Laurence Holder, c. 1980
      - Whispers Want to Holler by Martha Effinger, 2001-2002, Undated
      - Zora by Laurence Holder, 1981
      - Zora: The Darktown Strutter by Laurence Holder, 1981-1999
      - Zora Neale Hurston: The Story of Zora Neale Hurston by Laurence Holder, 1990
    - Not Performed
      - 6'9" by Eugene Mackey, 1983
      - 9/11 - A Day in the Life of a People by Charles Dumas, 2002
      - 1950s Doo Wop (The Fabulous Music of the Fifties) by Spero Criezis, Undated
      - ...Acted Within Proper Departmental Procedure by John H. Redwood, 1990
      - Ace by David Rambeau, 1988
      - Absinthe: A Play in Two Acts by Joe Musso, 2008
      - The Adventures of Umar and Nandi Episode Two Hare-Rambee by Charles Michael Moore, 1995
      - Acts by Gregory K. Allen, 1997, Undated
      - Action Not Affirmed: A Three Act Play by Derl G. Hunt, Ph.D and Lawrence C. Howard, Ph.D, Undated
      - Aftermath: A Three Act Play by Rudy Gray, 1992
      - Alterations by Michael Abbensetts, 1977
      - All Will Be Clear in Birmingham by Benard Cummings, 2004
      - All Over by Jamie J. Brunson, 2008
      - Ain't Got Time to Die and White Chocolate by Samuel L. Kelly, 1999
      - The American Dream or Cultural Reality of America arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, Undated
      - America, the Land of the Free? by Jacqui Walker, Undated
      - American Menu by Don Wilson Glenn, 2000
      - Ancestors Walking by Valerie Lawrence, Undated
      - And the Tree Grows Strong: The Stories of Nine African-American Women Who Raised Their Grandchildren by Robert Gorczyca, 2004
      - Antigone by Sopholes, Undated
      - The Anyway You Want it Barber Shop copyright "Orgaz" production, 1992
      - Arborophilia, or the Chopping Block by Jacob M. Appel, 2008
      - Avalon Court by Gladys Thomas, Undated
      - The Azuza Street Revival by André Joseph Seymour, c. 1992
      - Back in the Day by Eugene Dillanado, 1995
      - Baccalaureate by William Branch, 1975
      - The Ballad of Emmett Till by Ifa Bayeza, 2010
      - The Bathroom Cleaner author not listed, Undated
      - Bayou Relics by Elizabeth Brown, 1983
      - The Beautiful LaSalles by Michael Dinwiddie, c. 2001
      - Bedtime Story by Tsehaye Geralyn Herbert, 1993
      - Begin the Beguine: A Quartet of One-Act Plays by Kathleen Collins, 1984
      - Behind Closed Doors by Rob Penny, Undated
      - Benjamin Franklin Abolistionist; Eighteenth Century Africans in Motion by Amanda Kemp, Undated
      - Bessie By Kwesi Cameron, 1995
      - Bill Pickett: Being a True and Historical Account of the Legend as Recalled by Himself by Bill Harris, 1991
      - Billy Buck Board and His Traveling Minstrel Show by Thomas Martell Brimm, Undated
      - Birth by Michelle Agostini, 1995
      - Bishop by Javon Johnson, 1999
      - The Bitches Brew of 79 a Vintage Wine by William F. Mayfield, 1978
      - Black Boy "A Negro Childhood and Youth" arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1978
      - Black History Month in Apartment Two-Thirteen by Keith Antar Mason, c. 1996
      - Black Nativity by Langston Hughes, Undated
      - Black Notes: (From the Pages of Marta Effinger), author not listed, Undated
      - Black Pride by Mark Clayton Southers, Undated
      - Black Studies by Sybil Berry, 1993
      - Blasted by Frank Hightower, 2010
      - Bloods and Crips, author not listed, 1992
      - Boochie by Mari Evans, 1985
      - Boppin in Lil Hayti by Rob Penny, 1993
      - Bourbon on the Border by Pearl Cleage, 1997
      - Brazilian Rendezvou by Ernest McCarty, Undated
      - The Break of Day by Elizabeth Brown-Guillory, 2006, Undated
      - Brer Rabbit, A Black Ensemble Theatre Adaptation, Undated
      - The Bridal Shower by Robin Allen, 1999
      - The Bridge Party by Sandra Seaton, 1989
      - Broken Pieces by Gerald Irvin, Undated
      - Brothers and Sisters Soul Traveling Circus by Mario M. King, 1986
      - Burning Wood by Erick Irvis, 2006
      - But We Don't Do Those Things by Ardener M. Taylor, 1990
      - Camp Logan by Celeste Bedford Walker, Undated
      - Candy Lips & Hallelujah by Afaa Michael Weaver, 1997
      - The Cattle Car by Joee A. Hall-Hoxter, 1987, 1990
      - Ceremonies in Dark Old Men by Lonne Elder III, Undated
      - Change is Gonna Come arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 2002
      - Change is Revolution by Charles Heyward and Melvin Howard, Undated
      - Cherry Pie by Val Coleman, 2004
      - Children of the Poor, author not listed, Undated
      - Chillin' at the Playground, author not listed, Undated
      - Choices, author not listed, Undated
      - Choreopoem and Coropoem by Norma Jean Barnes and Vernell A. Lillie, 1997
      - A Christening Story By Erick Q. Irivs, 2007
      - Circus of Colors (A Hairstory) or Growns of Glory (A Hairstory) - her hair is a poem by Rob Penny, Undated
      - Class by Franklin Anderson, 1992
      - Cleo Patrick by Leah Hollis, 1991
      - The Closer the Kin by J.E. Franklin, 1990
      - CODA: A Comedy with Jazz by Bill Harris, 1990
      - The Colored Section by Thomas Meloncon, 1993
      - College Suite, author not listed, Undated
      - Collage by Sybil Berry, 1993
      - Collage K-4 organized by Heather Lynn McNeish and Youthworks Play, Undated
      - Collage for K through 5th Grade "Life is A Beautiful Thing," author not listed, Undated
      - Color Me Black arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, Undated
      - Color Me Dorothy by Cliff Roquemore, Undated
      - Colorblind by Kimberly S. Wood, Undated
      - The Colors of Your Life by Bruce Crowther, 1996, 1999
      - Colours by R. Ashton "Wraggs" Wall, 2000
      - Coming Apart Together by Paula Materre, Undated
      - Coming Home by Gladys Thomas, Undated
      - Community Kitchen by Alex Foster, Undated
      - The Congo by Vachel Lindsay, The Raven by Edgar Allen Poe, and Freedom Road arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1978
      - Contrary to Popular Belief by Nathan James, Undated
      - Copy Cat by Dipo Kalejaiye, Undated
      - Crumbs from the Table of Joy by Lynn Nottage, c. 1995
      - Crowns by Regina Taylor, 2003
      - A Dance Between Friends by Vanessa A. Spencer, 2005
      - Dance of the Blues Dead by Rob Penny, Undated
      - The Dark at the Top of the Stairs by William Inge, Undated
      - David and Dianna by Gladys Thomas, Undated
      - The Dead that Never Dies by Rob Penny, Undated
      - Deal! by Ida Shepherd, Undated
      - The Death of the Last Black Man by Suzan-Lori Parks, Undated
      - Deeds of Blackness by Rob Penny, Undated
      - Deep River by Joanne M. Braxton, c. 2000
      - Denmark by Charles Smith, 2005, 2006
      - The Difference by Von. H. Washington, 1987
      - Dignity is Ours, We are Workin' Hard, We're Together and We Mean Business Now! arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1995
      - Dinah! by Ernest McCarty, 2004
      - Disciple Son by Gregory Kahlil Kareem Allen, Undated
      - The Dismissal by Olis Vincent Eaglin, Undated
      - Distant Voices by Celeste Bedford Walker, 1998
      - Disturbing the Peace (An American Dream) and Getting Back (A Fantasy for Theatre) by Shirley M. Kreidwise, 1986, 1988
      - Doctor B.S. Black by Carlton Molette II and Barbara Molette, 1973
      - Don't Make Me Over author not listed, Undated
      - Dream arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1968, 1979
      - Dream of Ophelia by Sybil J. Roberts, Undated
      - Drink the Contents of the Vial by Lynda Patton, 1981
      - The Drums of Sweetwater by Thomas Meloncon, 1994
      - Ed-Med, Undated
      - The Electronic Nigger by Ed Bullins, 1968, c. 2010
      - An Elegance of Cannibals by Robert Lesser, Undated
      - Elephant Man by George Pomerance, 1979
      - Endless Trane by Clyde Davis, 2004
      - Enlarged Heart, David and Goliath, and Uh-Oh, author not listed, 2003
      - Essential Personnel by A.L. Letson, Jr., Undated
      - The Eunuchs by Thomas D. Pawley, c. 1978, 1989
      - Evolution to Revolution by Curtiss E. Porter, 1969
      - The Exchange, author not listed, Undated
      - The Exile of King Harold by Austin Sills, 1998
      - The Eye of Gabriel by Femi Euba, 1995
      - The Family by Jeffrey C. Benson Jr., Undated
      - Family Circle by Tori Denson, Undated
      - The Fanatic (or, Testifyin') by Ben Caldwell, 1967
      - Fantasy by Bob Gore, Undated
      - A Fat Tuesday's Night Dream by Valon Pennington, Undated
      - The Fear in Percy Childs by Mark Southers, Undated
      - The Fear in Percy Reems by Austin Sills, 1992
      - Fences by August Wilson, Undated
      - A Fictional Meeting with Frederick Douglass, W.E.B. DuBois, Booker T. Washington, author not listed, Undated
      - Firehouse by Frank Cucci, c. 1973
      - Flight by Charlayne Woodard, 2006
      - A Fool for a Client, author not listed, Undated
      - For the Love Of...Friends by Nailah "Blu" Lewis, Undated
      - Forest City, author not listed, Undated
      - Foundling by Robert McAndrew, 2000
      - Frank Talk by Paul R. Strothers, Undated
      - A Free Encounter with War Won't Hurt You by Rob Penny, Undated
      - The Freedom Road arranged by Vernell A. Lillie, 1978
      - Freeman in Paris by Herb Newsome, 2008
      - From the Harlem Renaissance to the 1990s (In Celebration of the Rich Cultural Heritage of African Americans) arranged and directed by Vernell A. Lillie and Shona Sharif, Undated
      - From the Mississippi Delta by Dr. Endesha Ida Mae Holland, 1992
      - A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to the Forum by Bert Shevelove and Larry Gelbart, 1963
      - Get Ready by Jaye Steward and Joe Plummer, 1994
      - Getting Back: A Fantasy for Theatre by Shirley M. Kreidwise, 1986
      - God's Carved in Ebony: The Testimony of Mr. Amanda Berry Smith, The Singing Pilgrim, author not listed, Undated
      - Goin' Back in Time by Kathleen Shaw, 1993
      - Goin' Home to Freedom: An Adaptation of Uncle Tom's Cabin for Modern Audiences by Bruce A. McConachie, 1985
      - The Golden Years author not listed, Undated
      - A Good Quick Feel: A Then We Build On A Plan (Black Hope*) by Rob Penny, Undated
      - Goreé Crossing by Paul Carter Harrison, 1990
      - The Great Black Baseball Diamond by Sage Berlin, c. 1994
      - The Greatest Love of All, author not listed, Undated
      - Grow in Hope and Grace arranged by Lisa D. Winstead, Undated
      - Hambone by Javon Johnson, 1999
      - Hamhocks by S. Garrett Robinson, 1967
      - Hard Bops and Poetic Blues by Rob Penny, Undated
      - Harlem After Hours by Audrey Lawson and Celeste Bedford Walker, c. 2003
      - Harlem Dream arranged by Rhona Wilber, 1968
      - Harlem Night Song, author not listed, Undated
      - The Healing author not listed, Undated
      - Heaven by Jo Ann Dearing and Merrill Green, Undated
      - Hell's Hole, author not listed, Undated
      - Hennesey Street by Rebecca Redshaw, 1997
      - Here Am I, Send Me by Benard Cummings, 1999
      - Hi-Hat Hattie! by Larry Parr, 1990
      - Hi Midnight by Warren B. Burdine, Undated
      - Highway of Tough Love by Rachel Roebuck, Undated
      - Hobo King by Javon Johnson, Undated
      - Holding Court: Why Black Men Play Basketball by Brian Quenton Thorne, c. 2002, 2004
      - Homerun! by David A. Perkins, 1991
      - A Hopeful Interview with Satan by OyamO, 1986
      - Hopes and Dreams, K-4th Grade Performance, author not listed, Undated
      - The Hooch by Charles Michael Moore, 1978
      - The Hopscotch Place, performance for K-5 arranged, by Contemporary Black Drama Theatre Company, Undated
      - The Hypothetical Ginko Biloba Cello Who Fell in Love with a City Bus, author not listed, Undated
      - Images, author not listed, Undated
      - In the Garden of Ruby by Frank F. Hightower, Undated
      - In the Last Days by Norman Harrison Jordan, 1971, 1992
      - In the Light of the Day by Robin Hampton Allen, 1996
      - In Pursuit of Justice: A One-Woman Play about Ida B. Wells by Wendy D. Jones, 1995
      - In White America by Martin Duberman, Undated
      - Incandescent Tones and From Dirt to Diamonds by Risë Collins, 1981
      - Inherit the Wind by Jerome Lawrence and Robert Lee, Undated
      - The Interviews by Brian Jagger, 2008
      - It Takes a Village by Mark A. Jones, 2007
      - It's Rhyme Time by Azizi Powell, 2005
      - It's A Wonderful Life by Michael Tilford, 1990
      - James: A Soul on Fire by Howard Simon, c. 2000
      - Jar on the Floor by Cheryl West, 1992
      - Jerry Black, Investigative Reporter by William F. Mayfield, 2002
      - Jitney! by August Wilson, 1979
      - Joe Turner's Come and Gone by August Wilson, Undated
      - Johnnie B. Goode by Thomas Meloncon, 1995
      - Josh: The Black Babe Ruth by Michael A. Jones, 2008
      - Judgement Day by James Weldon Johnson, 2003
      - Judgement at Nuremberg by Abby Mann adapted by Vernell A. Lillie, 1973
      - Judgement at Neuremberg by Abby Mann, Undated
      - July Jones by Edward M. Chambers, c. 1985
      - Juneteenth Jubilee Rising by Carol Eisom, 1997
      - Kate's Sister by Maisha Baton, c. 1987
      - Keep Going On by Roger Perez, Undated
      - Kid Zero by Ifa Bayeza, 2010
      - Kids World by Vernell A. Lillie, c. 1982
      - Lady Day at Emerson's Bar and Grill by Lanie Robertson, 1989
      - The Legacy of Absalom Jones and Mahalia Jackson, Undated
      - Let the Children Play...Let the Children Sing...Let the Children Live! arranged by Ellonda Green, Undated
      - Let Me Live by Charles A. OyamO Gordan, 1991
      - A Life to Live arranged by Ellonda Green, Undated
      - Robert Smalls: Legend of the Black Mariner by Wali Jamal Abdullah, Undated
      - The Length of Our Blackness by Rob Penny, Undated
      - Killingsworth by Eugene Lee, 1986
      - The Ladder, author not listed, Undated
      - The Lesson by Ionesco, Undated
      - Lilac Samba by Francesca Sanders, 2005
      - Linty Lucy by Rudy Gray, 1999
      - Little Black Boys by William F. Mayfield, 1985
      - Little Sallie Walker by Marta Effinger, Undated
      - Loneliness, author not listed, Undated
      - The Long Lonesome Ride of Charley Young by Thomas Pawley, 1990
      - Longstreet by Stirling Silliphant, 1970
      - Look Your Best; or A Good Black "What's Yr Hair Like After U Wash It?" (Valerie Lawrence, Poet) by Rob Penny, Undated
      - Looking Out of the Window by Herbert Payne, 1982, 1986
      - Loud Enough for God to Hear by Thomas Bryant, Undated
      - Love Tap by Gred Ganier, Undated
      - The Madwoman of Challot by Jean Giraudoux, c. 1947
      - Magnolia Aid Society by Valerie Lawrence Williams, Undated
      - A Man Among Men by David Perkins and Milton Henderson Jr., 1988
      - The Man Who Lived Underground by Richard Wright, Undated
      - Martin Luther King, Jr.: A Nō Play, author not listed, Undated
      - A Matter of Conscience by Veona Thomas, 1985
      - Medea by Euripides, Undated
      - The Middle Man by Harmon S. Watson, 1972
      - The Middle Passage by John Spears, Undated
      - Misunderstanding by Brandt E. Washington, Undated
      - Mitote: A One Act Historically Based Drama by Maisha Baton, 1984, 2000
      - Monsieur, The Con Man by Roger Furman, Undated
      - Moony's Kid Don't Cry author not listed, Undated
      - Mountaintop author not listed, Undated
      - Mulatto by Langston Hughes, Undated
      - Murder at the Cathedral: Who Killed the Community Organizer, author not listed, Undated
      - Muses by Gail A. Burton, 1995
      - Next Stop, Ellipses by Javon Johnson, 1998
      - Nine Days in the Sun by Mark Clayton Southers, 2004
      - Nine Lives, author not listed, Undated
      - No Crime in the Streets, author not listed, Undated
      - No Heroes Parade by A. Edward Upshur III, 1997
      - Nongogo by Athol Fugard, 1974
      - Now We Are Not Alone Anymore by Gladys Thomas, Undated
      - Nzinga and the Festival of Gifts by Thomas Meloncon, 1991
      - Odella by William F. Mayfield, 1985
      - Odella's Video World by William F. Mayfield, 1987
      - Of Gods and Supergods by David Lee Lindsey, 1999
      - And Ole Soul a Young Spirit by John Henry Redwood, 2003
      - On Earth a Little Space by Virginia Cunningham, 2000
      - On the Edge of No Tomorrow by A. L. Letson Jr., Undated
      - On Taylor Street by Reginald Gregory Small, 2010
      - One Love by Jeffrey C. Benson, Jr., 1999
      - One Nickel On This Wise by Charles Michael Moore, 1974